Patriarchy is what drives people to commit a lot of the acts that lead us to prison.
And patriarchy is what leads us to believe in prisons in the first place.
I'm not even going to talk. Keep going.
In my cultural context, as a young person who grew up in L.A.,
I was seeking to be a worthwhile human by being a quote unquote real man.
And real men had money and I was broke living in cars and shit.
So I decided to rob stores, you know, as a culture.
We also believe that domination is power.
So when somebody, quote unquote, hurts us, and I put it in quotes because most people in L.A. were not affected by my robbery at all.
We have to, quote unquote, hurt them back in order for there to be, quote unquote, justice.
And that is it is upon that idea that we build these castles of shame that we call prisons.
But if we saw power as connection, if we saw power as integrity, then rather than like I need to dominate you and force this, quote unquote, badness out of you,
it would be like you are a legitimate human being trying to suit your needs just like I am.
So what need are you trying to suit and what needs to be transformed so you can do that in a way that doesn't harm others?